Bruno Henriques

27 Years Old Lisbon, Portugal

■ bphenriques@outlook.com (+351) 915 362 901

Ophenriques in /in/bphenriques Ophenriques.github.io

SUMMARY

Organized, detail-oriented and collaborative Software Engineer with 2+ experience building iOS applications and 3+ experience in designing, delivering and supporting products in the industry of Financial Crime and Cloud Contact Center.

Keywords: Kotlin, Spring Boot, Scala, Java, Redis, Elastic Stack, Docker.

Interests: System Design, Stream Processing, Functional Programming.

EDUCATION

TÉCNICO LISBOA

MSc in Computer Science

Software Engineer Intelligent Systems

Finished Nov 2016 | Lisbon, Portugal Final Average: 17 out of 20

BSC IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Finished July 2014 | Lisbon, Portugal Final Average: 17 out of 20

ABBOTSHOLME

ENGLISH LANGUAGE PROGRAMME August 2010 | Staffordshire, England

LANGUAGES

Portuguese: Native

English: Full Working Level Proficiency

SKILLS

Backend:

Java, Scala, Kotlin, Spring Boot, RabbitMQ, Kafka.

Data Management:

Redis, PostgreSQL, Elastic Stack.

Mobile:

iOS, Swift, Objetive-C.

Other:

AWS, Docker, Ansible, Kubernetes.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TALDESK | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May 2019 - Present (14 months) | Lisbon

- Design, build and maintain Talkdesk's automated dialing solution;
- Member of the on-call prevention team.

Technologies: Kotlin, Spring Boot, Redis, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Docker, Ruby.

FEEDZAI | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

July 2017 - May 2019 (approx. 2 years) | Lisbon

- Design, build and maintain Feedzai's Analytics solution using **Elastic stack**;
- Maintain and implementation of new features for the merchant's product;
- Member of the on-call prevention team.

Technologies: Java, Scala, Elastic Stack, RabbitMQ, **Docker**, Akka, Ansible, PostgreSQL, AWS, Tableau.

CARBON BY BOLD | IOS DEVELOPER

December 2016 - July 2018 (8 months) | Lisbon

Developed and released three iOS applications.

Technologies: iOS, Swift, Realm, Objective-C, Core Location, RxSwift, SignalR.

ANITA BORG | Google Summer of Code IOS Mentor

March 2016/2017 - September 2016/2017 (12 months) | Remote

Technologies: iOS, Swift, Core Data, Realm.

ANITA BORG | GOOGLE SUMMER OF CODE IOS STUDENT

May 2015 - September 2015 (5 months) | Remote

Technologies: iOS, Swift, Core Data.

FENIXEDU | Técnico Lisboa iOS Developer

October 2014 - November 2015 (13 months) | Lisbon

Developed and released the official Técnico Lisboa iOS App.

Technologies: iOS, Swift, Core Data, Realm, EventKit.

GAIPS INESC-ID | RESEARCH SUMMER INTERNSHIP (VIDEO ■)

July 2014 - August 2014 (2 months) | Oeiras

Technologies: Python, C++, ROS, OpenCV.

AWARDS & CERTIFICATES

Sep 2018 Elasticsearch Eng. I and II (Training) May 2018 Functional Prog. in Scala

Dec 2017 ScrumMaster®

March 2016 8th place (out of 13)

Elasticsearch® Coursera

Scrum Alliance®

Unbabel NLP Challenge